what's up folks. In this video, we're going to talk about
building agent workflows in eight levels of complexity. This is a
follow up to one of my best videos from my channel, called
building agents in three levels of complexity. And today, we're
going to talk about how to go from a simple LMM call, all the way
up to an agent workflow that uses an agent as a step. We're going
to talk through the papers and the a little bit of the theory in a
lot of the practice, right? Everything is going to be from
scratch. Meaning we are they're going to use the basic and lame
APIs, or we're just going to build stuff ourselves in pure
Python. All right. So we're going to start easy, we're going to
set up our environment variable for open API key. And we're going
to run this. And now we're going to basically just write a
simple LMM call. And that's super easy, right? We just have
to import the open API, set up our client. And then we're going
to write a little function. And I'm going to name the functions
like level one, level two, level three to like organize our
thoughts. And the first one's called level one. And it's the
basic LMM call, which essentially just calls the responses API
from open AI, uses the GPT five mini model, sends a simple
prompt and gets a response back. Pretty basic. So now we're
going to call it like what is an agent workflow. And when we
run it, we'll take a few seconds. And we'll just provide us with
the response, pretty basic simple stuff. We specify the model,
the input, and that's it. Right, we can use this to do things
like summarize, extract a little bit of information. And we're
limited by the prompting mechanics of the specific API. So
we're just going to prompt and give responses back. So it's
text goes in, text comes out. Okay, great. However, now when we
go to level two, now we can start thinking about how can we
chain these LMM costs to make something a little bit more
powerful, right? And a very cool resource for this topic is
building effective agents by anthropic, where they talk about
workflow agents went to use them, how they work, and they go
from scratch. And this article definitely inspired my desire
to do this video that I'm doing right now. So go check it out.
All right, so chaining LMM calls is super easy. All we got to
do is essentially what we're going to do is we're going to set
up a function that does the LLM call, so takes in some input
and provides some output. And this calls the opening API like we
did before, use the GPT five mini model and sends a prompt and
gets a response back easy. However, the level true is all
about chaining as many LLM calls as we want. So for that, what
we're going to do is we're going to take we're going to start
with an input in a list of prompts that we want to chain
together. Then what we're going to do is we're going to loop
over these prompts. And for each prompt, we're going to take a
result of calling the making a call to the LLM call function
with that prompt on and save the result as an input for the
next call. So that means that we start with the result as the
input, right? And then we call the first prompt. And then the
next one is going to take in the result of the previous one as
the input for the next. And we're going to do that for as many
prompts as we have on the list of prompts that we're going to
give this function as an input. And then we're going to print
that out. And that's pretty much what it is. And for the
example usage, I'm putting here an input topic like a Gentic
workflow. And then the prompt is first, we're going to create a
three bullet point essay plan for this topic. And then we're
going to write the essay following the plan strictly. All
right. And when we call this, right, so I can call it with the
input and the list of prompts, this is what happens. So what
we're going to see is that first, we're going to see the
output of the first call to the LLM, which essentially is going
to create a plan for the essay. And then the second one is going
to write the essay following the structure from the previous
output. So the essay that we're going to write now is going to be
based on this essay plan. So it's going to be like defining the
scope and then arguing the benefits and then examining the
challenges. So that's pretty much all it's going to do. So we're
going to wait a few seconds. I'm probably going to skip this.
Perfect. So now we can see that the first output was the plan
and the second output was the actual essay. So our chaining
works. And we can do this for all sorts of lists of prompts
for whatever workflow we're trying to build. All right. Now,
number three starts to get interesting because we start
routing at a LEM calls. So routing essentially means this.
If we go back to the building effective agents and we go to the
router pattern section.
Router here, we go here, we get augmented chaining, there
you go, routing. So here we have an LLM first. And what the LLM
is going to do is going to route the input to one of as many as
we want LLMs, not as many as we want, but like to one of X
LLMs. And one of those LLMs is going to take in the input. It's
going to provide us with an output as simple as that. So to do
that, all we got to do is we set up a little dictionary that's
going to contain a tag that indicates what is the selected
prompt for the LLM that has been routed. And in this case, I
have two simple tags, two simple classifications, right? We
have a coding prompt and a math prompt. So if the router
identifies that the input is related to coding, the router is
going to output something that can be parsed as coding. And
then we're going to, the prompt is going to be take this coding
problem and produce a solution invite. So essentially, if the
input is a coding problem or something related to producing
code, the the router is going to output coding. And if the
problems that are math, the router is going to output math.
That's pretty much all it does. Obviously, it could be a little
bit smarter input here, something like if none of these
topics are like, if the input is not about any of these topics,
we can produce an output like default, like none or something
like that, but we don't really need to do that. So now level
three, which is routing is going to take in some input in this
dictionary containing the coding and the math prompts. And now
we're going to write a little selector prompt, which is going
to say, analyze the input and classify it as one of the
following categories. Then we're going to list the router keys,
right, the keys from this dictionary. So coding and math.
And then we give an example just to make sure that the model is
going to get it right. Okay. So we show it like input, write a
Python function to read a file and then output coding, input,
salty equation, two x plus three equal 11. And then the output
is pretty simple, right? And then we start with the input given
by the user. Now what we do is we make a call to the other
lab, which hopefully will return either coding or math. And
then we print, we print that out so that we can make sure that
everything's working. And then we identify the selected prompt
from the dictionary based on the key that's going to come out of
this LLM call. And finally, we make the LLM call and return
that. So the output of the LLM call with the selected prompt
from this dictionary, which is going to be either the value for
this coding prompt or the math prompt. And the input given by
the user has the input that's going to be processed by this
prompt with this LLM call, which is the call to this function
that we wrote back here, called LLM call, which uses the
GPT five mini model to process the output process the input. So
when we do that, so when we do that, no, let me just go here,
running the following prompt. So we're going to run that. And
now we're going to use it. So I'm going to say write some code,
they can load a PDF and extract the headers of the document. And
then I give the dictionary that contains the possible routes.
Okay. And we're going to print that output. So now we're going
to send that out.
All right, perfect. So we're done running. So as you can see,
the output was coding. And then it ran the output for the
coding prompt. And it produced some very reliable output,
produced something that makes sense with the prompt. So we're
done. This is pretty good. Now, it's important to note that
these two examples for chaining and routing, I adapted them from
a really cool cool book from a cookbook from anthropic, which
you can check out on this article as well. Let me just
show you cookbook. There you go. So if you're going here, so
this is the cookbook. And I have it referenced in the notebook.
And I'm going to make the notebook available on GitHub. So
you you have access to it. And this example was from the basic
workflow notebook. However, they did this tailor to the cloud
API. And I did it tailored to the opening API. But it's pretty
similar with the difference that they did some XML parsing. And
I'm not doing that in the example we're seeing now. But
this is an awesome notebook. If you want to do stuff from scratch,
this is a great starting point. So going back, now we're going to
go to level four, which is when we combine LLMs with the
information of some available functions. And we put that
information inside of the prompt to the model to see if the
model is able to make calls to those functions. And the
inspiration for that was from a paper called two former, where
language models taught themselves how to use tools, a pretty
simple way. All they did was to provide outputs as text, which
were inside of the text, they had special strings that could be
parsed into function calls that we can run with Python code.
Okay, like you can see here, this is this thing in purple can be
run as a Python function, which calls this Q and API or Q and a
function. Okay, so inspired by this paper, we're going to do a
very simple example. So we're going to load up some imports.
And what we're going to do here is essentially, we start with
something very silly simple function, which essentially is
going to set us up in the in a base directory. And then if it's
not, it's going to handle some errors. The most important
thing is that we're going to write two functions, one to read
files and one to write files. So we're going to read a file. So
this function is going to take in a file path. And it's going to
set the base directory and then read the file on side of that
path. Same thing for the right file function, it's going to set
the base directory and then it's going to write a file in the
specified file path. Okay, pretty simple, pretty easy. So now,
what we're going to do is the level four is going to be about
merging the LLM with the functions inside of the prompt. So
for that, all we're going to do is we're going to write a
little piece of code that gets the function as a string. So I use
the inspect module, which I didn't know existed, honestly, up
to today. So that was pretty cool. Because in the previous
example that I did on my latest video, my lesson, my last video
on this topic, I actually put the functions as strings inside
of the prompt manually. So it's nice to know that I can do
that programmatically. Now, I have a full prompt that contains
the information about the functions to write files and read
files. Okay. And what we're going to do with that is we're
going to send input to the OpenAI Responses API with the
GPT five mini mod. And we're going to say you're a helpful
assistant that can write and read files. This used to be the
system message from the previous version of their API. But now
they change it to instructions. It's the same thing. So now this
model has the information about the two functions available
plus has instructions about using these tools. So we're going
to see if this model is able to produce an output that we can
transform into an execution of the function indicated. So let's
see if that's possible. So let's see. This call level for a
Lamb function in prompt takes an input prompt like this, write a
file called test the content hello world. And then I give it a
list of the tools available. So write file and read file. Okay.
And what we're going to do now. Yeah, we're going to now we're
going to run this. And we're going to see the output of the
function call. We're going to see the output of this function.
So as you can see, the output of this function is exactly what
we need, which is a string that exactly reads as the calling of
the right function for the task. So what we're going to do is
we're going to use Python's built in exact module, which you can
check out in the Python documentation, which essentially
supports dynamic execution of Python code. Okay, so supports
dynamic execution Python code. That's what it does. So we're
going to use it to execute this string that indicates that we
have to write the file. Okay, so when we do that, what happens
is that we execute the action. So if we do a cat on the output of
test.txt to see if it was created, you see that it was
created. So it's perfect. So what I want you to start seeing
is that we're evolving from calling LLM APIs to trying to
give LLM the ability to perform actions. But we are in the
initial stages of that. Let's see how we can evolve even
further. Now we're going to look at something called structured
outputs. Now structure outputs, it's a very interesting thing.
What it does is essentially give these LLM the ability to take
unstructured data and produce structured data, so structured
outputs. That's what it does. And there's no official paper on
this topic, which I found kind of weird, but I think one of the
best resources that you can see that are open source on the
topic are either this JSON form or GitHub repo from hugging
face, where they show a bulletproof way to generate structured
JSON from language models. It's super cool, and you can see a
little bit about it. But the major source for knowledge on this
topic has been the OpenAI Docs on structure outputs when they
released it in 2024. And essentially what you see is that
you can produce structured output. So an object given something
called a JSON schema. And what the JSON schema is is
essentially something that defines, okay, what is the, what is
the structure of my object? Okay. So essentially, what that
means is that we can indicate to the model, look, I want to
produce an output that has this structure, and the model is
going to produce an output that adheres to the structure that I
want. So for example, I'm going to transform the previous
example that we're doing into a structured output problem. So I'm
going to create a class called right file operation. And I'm
going to be using a module, a very cool package in Python
called by dentic. So what by dentic is by dentic. So by dentic
is essentially a data validation library in Python that works
amazingly well with LLM's. It's probably one of the most
important packages out there on the LLM era that we're living
right now. So what we're going to do is we're going to create a
little object called right file operation. It's going to have
two attributes, the file path, which contains the file where
the file should be saved, and the contents of that file. So this
is mimicking the operation of writing a file with the right
file function. But instead of calling that function, we're
producing the arguments to call that function. Hopefully, you
see where we're going with this. And we're going to do the
same with the reap file function. So reap file operation in the
file path. Now, we're going to write a prompt like write a file
called test2.txt with the content hello world again. And we're
going to make a call to the open AI responses API. But with the
little added feature, we're going to set the best format for
the output of this model to adhere to the right file
operation object. So that means that this output is going to
contain these attributes file path and content. Hopefully, being
tailored to the prompt that we're writing right here. So the
file path hopefully is going to be test2.txt. And the contents
are going to be hello world again. So now we're going to do
that. And then we're going to see what that output looks like.
Perfect. So as you can see, we were able to obtain exactly
what we wanted. So we obtained it programmatically, because we
created something that's a structured object represented by
response dot output parts, which if we look at it is actually the
object that we were hoping for. So if I create this here and I
output, you can see that it says the object, it contains the
things that we were looking for. So now we can write level five.
And level five is going to be about leveraging this to execute
an action, similarly to what we did before with the functions
inside of the prompt. But this time we're leveraging structured
outputs instead. So we're going to write the response to the
LMBPI. And we're going to write the format to be right file
operation. And then we're going to get the arguments back
programmatically. And then we're going to call the function
right file super simple, super easy. So now we're going to call
this and see what happens. Hopefully what's going to happen
is that the model is going to extract this as file path. And
this has the content of the file. And then it's going to
execute the function correctly. Now, obviously, if I was doing
something more serious, I would have to put a bunch of error
handling here and a bunch of other stuff. But for now, I think
that this is more than enough. So we're going to call this
it seems like it worked. So we're going to test that out. Perfect
it works. So now we're going to go even further. So we're going
to go to level six and level six is function calling. Now, it's
important to note that I'm talking about structured outputs
before I'm talking about function calling, which is a choice I
made. But chronologically, function calling came first, it
was released in June of 2023 in the open API. If we go to the
release post, we can see here, June, June 2023, the function
calling API was released by OpenAI. And if we go to the
release post by structure outputs, that was in August of
2024. However, conceptually structure outputs underlies
what makes function calling possible, because it's the
ability to produce outputs that adhere to a certain JSON
schema structure. So what is the function calling? We already
saw that in practice, we saw that we can transform the outputs
of an LLM into calls to functions. So function calling is
just the integration of the capability directly into the
LLM API, in this case, the opening API. And we're going to
do that by leveraging what the open API allows us to do. And
we're going to make cost of functions, we're going to allow
LLMs to take actions autonomously with this capability
similarly to what we did before. So to do that, we're going to
set up a better way to inform the LLM about the available tools
or functions. And then we're going to see if the LLM is able
to call them. So to do that, we got the final list of callable
tools for the model. And that list is going to be a list of
dictionaries that have a type, in this case, function, and then
we say write file, we give a description, and we give the
parameters that go with a function. So this is similar to
put the to putting the functions inside of the prompt, but we do
it as a JSON object to be a little bit more structurally
sound. So we're doing that for both functions, we're defining
the required parameters, the contents of each of the parameters
or if things good. So once we've done that, what we're going to
do next is we're going to write down, I'm going to rewrite the
read and write file functions just to be thorough. And what we're
going to do now is we're going to set up a list of inputs
through the model, which is just going to have one input. And
the inputs can to be create a file called test function
calling.txt with the content level six function calling. That's
it. So now we're going to make a call to the open API. We're going
to set the tools parameter to the list that we created called
tools. And we're going to set two choice to auto, because that
sets the choice of a to call to be automatically selected by the
model, in this case, by GPT five mini. And then we're going to
give the input as this little list of inputs, which could be
just the just the prompt itself. It doesn't have to be this list
of dictionaries. Okay, however, I think the responses API is
kind of backwards compatible with the previous version. And
that's why this thing still works. So now we're going to do
that. And then what we're going to do is we're going to save
the functional call outputs for subsequent requests. So stick
with me on this. So here's the thing, when we get the output
from the model, we're going to inspect to see if any of the
items inside of the output, which is going to be a list of
objects, any of them should have a type of function call, which
indicates that a call to a function was made. And then we're
going to inspect the names of those function calls. And if they
match the functions that we actually have, we are going to
take care of the part of making of calling those functions. So
we're going to say, okay, let's obtain the arguments that the
model determine should be used for the function call. And then
here, I'm doing it kind of like semi manually, because I already
know for the right file, what are the arguments? So I'm taking
them here like this. And then I'm calling I'm making myself the
call to the right file function. Now this is very similar to what
we did before, but we're leveraging the API to be more
deterministic about these executions of these functions. And
they were appending the outputs of these executions, so that the
model can compile the initial input and the outputs of the
functions to produce a comprehensive response to the
user. So we're doing a similar thing to read file. And then
finally, we make a second call to the LLM containing
everything that happened, including the initial prompt in
the function calls and their outputs. So now we can inspect
what the final output looks like. So I'm going to run this.
And there you go. It seems like the file was created. And we
can test that and perfect. It was created. Awesome. So there you
go. Now it starts to get interesting, because now we've
learned about basic LLM calls, chaining calls, routing calls,
putting functions inside prompts, using structured outputs to
transform and structure data via LLM's into structured objects.
And we've learned about function calling with the open API. Now,
let's build a agent. Let's build something that can
autonomously, autonomously make decisions and execute actions
and loop over the usage of these tools and execution of
actions to perform complex tasks. So the inspiration for this
next demonstration comes from a really awesome paper called
React. And this paper, which I have it listed here in the
notebook, which is called synergizing reasoning and acting
language models. What this paper does is they show that there's
a way that you can prompt the model to incentivize the
interleaving of thoughts, like plans for what to do, and
actions, which mean essentially executing some programs and
function, which will lead to an observation that the model is
going to use to be able to get further and further in solving
the task. So this paper is really cool. And what you can do
with this is what we're going to try to do is we're going to
try to build from scratch only only using the LLM API in Python
code. This entire react agent loop, which is a really good way
to understand how modern agents work. So I'm going to, again,
write the read file, write file functions back into the cell
here just to be thorough. Then I'm going to write a little
mapping object here, which is essentially just dictionary
that maps the names read file and write file to the correct
corresponding functions. Okay. Now we're going to have a
list of tools, which is the same as we did before. Okay, it's
pretty similar to the thing that we did before. So it's the
write file read file to descriptions as dictionaries. Okay,
so these are the JSON schemas of those functions. Now, for the
instructions for this model, we're going to have a few things
that we need to address. The first one is this, your careful
system that can use tools to read and write files. Okay, great.
If a task involves files, call the appropriate tool with
precise arguments. After two calls, summarize results for the
user, only write files when explicitly asked or when
necessary to complete the task. This is just to increase the
chance of a good two calls. So the model being precise about
calling the right tools. And then if something is ambiguous,
ask a concise clarifying question. When you're done, respond
with final answer. And I'm doing this here just because we
want to be able to parse some indication that a loop of
actions should end. And we can actually provide an answer to
the user. So now I wrote this with AI and just to safely load
the JSON schemas of the tools that were going to be used. And
then we're going to have something to if a loop goes for too
long, we want to have something like this that summarizes
what happened to the model. And without overloading the context
window of the model, so all the text the model can read. And
now we're going to finally write level seven, the react agent
loop. And what we're going to have for this function is a
task prompt, which describes what the problem is. And then we're
going to set the maximum number of turns that the model can
actually loop and use tools to solve the task. Okay, I set the
default to eight, but you can do it for like three. And that should
be fine. Now we're going to start with that input. And here's
what we're going to do. We're going to loop over the maximum
amount of turns that we can do. And each turn involves making a
call to the LLM API, reading and executing the functions that
are called. And then seeing if we've reached the final answer, if
not, we're going to go yet. So for that, we're going to start
with calling the model using the similar structure that we did
before. And now, so what we're going to be doing here is we're
going to be taking all the function calls that we identifying
the model's response output. And we're going to execute those
function calls, just like we did in the previous example. So
we're going to identify them by the name. And then we're going to
use the pi tools mapping dictionary that we built for the
write file and read file. And then we're going to use that to get
the actual function to be able to execute that function. So you
execute the function, we write a little bit of some try
accept statements to make sure that we can handle some error
messages. And then we append the output of the execution of the
functions to the input list that the model is going to be able to
see at the end to be able to compile a proper response to the
user. And what we do lastly is if and when the model produces
the final answer text inside of the output, that means that we're
done, we don't have to loop anymore, and we can provide an
answer to the user. So we parse that from the output using the
rejects module. And then we return, and if we don't for some
reason get to get to an actual output from the agent after the
all of the terms that we set with the max_turns parameter, we
just stop because we reach the maximum. All right. So now, we're
going to set up a complex task that involves two actions,
right, reading a file and then writing a summary of it to another
file. And we're going to test it with our react agent loop. And
we're going to see if it works. Perfect. Seems like it works. And
we can test that by going to the summary file. We see that we
got the summary file. And we see that it's talking about
embeddings. If we go to the sample input file, we see that the
input was about embeddings. So it seems like it works. So this
is great. What we're going to do now is we're going to go to the
final level, let's say, which is the actual Agentec workflow. And
this is going to be an Agentec workflow that uses agents. But
instead of the end goal being the agent, the agent is just a step
in a more complex system that merges the idea of simpler steps
using just a simple LML call with possible agents, depending on
the routing mechanics of the previous input. What I mean by that
is we're going to take some input. And then we're going to use a
router LML call like we did in level three. Remember, we did first
test it for a LML call. And then we did a chaining of LML calls.
And the third example was the routing procedure, where it takes an input and
then it can route to one LML call or another. We're going to do that
same thing here. But this time, since we've learned about
structured outputs, we're going to be using structured outputs to do the
routing mechanics. And what we're going to do next is we're going to
route to either a jokes agent, which is going to be some agent that can
write to files and creates jokes or to a web search agent, which can
search the web and also write to files. Then the output is going to be produced
by either of those agents, depending on the input.
That's what we're going to do. So to start things off, we're going to set up
the routing mechanics. So to do that, we're going to set up a
class called router output. And this class is going to have one
attribute called category, which is going to be either the
string joke or the web search. So it's a simple classification
output. And then we're going to describe category of the input
joke or web search. And then finally, we're going to
make a test call to the LML to the OpenAI Responses API,
setting the text format to the router output to see if this thing works.
So I'm going to test that out right now. Perfect. It seems like it works.
It was able to identify that the input was about creating jokes.
Pretty simple problem. And now what we're going to do is we're going to set up
the tools for these agents. So for the Joker agent, it's just a simple
write file tool. And for the web search agent is the
write file tool and the ability to search the web, which in the OpenAI
Responses API, it already has a built-in tool for a web search, which we're
going to use. So that's what we have on the Joker
agent tools, pretty similar to what we did before. But this time is just for the
write file and web search, we have the write file tool.
And we have this, which is the statement that indicates the
OpenAI Responses API that the tool to use is the built-in
web search tool. Then I, this is just because we're doing
this from scratch. I did a little dictionary that
if the routing call is joke, we're going to route it to the Joker agent with
these instructions and these tools. And if it's web search, we're going to route
it to the web search agent with these instructions
and these tools. Pretty simple, right? So now we're going to run that.
All right. So after that, what we're going to do is we're going to set up the
this tool map variable, which is just a dictionary that maps the write file
to the function. So we run that. And now what we're going to do is we're going to
define a react agent loop similar to the one that we did before,
but with a catch. This is going to be a more modular
function that allows us to create specialized agents.
So it will take in the input. It will take in
the agent dictionary, which is going to be either this
or this, which essentially takes three keys, the name, the instructions and the
tools and the max turns, just like we did before.
And this is going to be very similar to before, but with the addition
that now we can actually make specialized agents based on the
custom set of instructions and a list of tools,
similar to what different frameworks do out there,
where you can create specialized agents with very simple input.
So we're going to set up our input list. We're going to set up the agent tools
by extracting it from the agent dictionary.
And then we're going to set up the loop similar to what we did before.
This is going to loop is going to make a call to the open API
with the instructions for the agent that will be
used, selected by the router call. And then we're going to
put that into the input list so that this
so that information will be stored in the
log of the agent. We're going to execute the function calls.
Remember folks that if the agent uses the web search tool,
this function call is this is not necessary because the web search
is executed by the opening API by default.
So this is just for functions that are defined outside of the scope of the
building tools. So then we're going to extract.
We're going to map it exactly similar to what we did before.
And the reason why I'm rewriting this is because I want to make each of these
levels kind of like self-contained. Then we're appending the outputs of the
function call execution of the function calls.
And we're doing similar to what we did before.
We're scraping the final answer. We're scraping the final answer with the rejects
module and then appending everything and
returning stopped if the maximum number of turns is
reached without a conclusion. Okay, perfect. So this looks good.
And now we can run this and we can finally write
the function that represents level 8 which is the
agentic workflow using this agent as a step. So
remember what we're building is a simple agentic workflow that takes
first a router which is going to use an element to route
the call to the input to either the jokes agent or the web search agent.
And from there we're going to provide a final output.
Super simple. So when we go back what we're going to do is we're going to
start with the router. So we're going to
obtain the classification either jokes or web search.
Then we're going to, based on that, we're going to select the appropriate agent
and the output is going to be the execution of that agent.
That's it. Super simple. Super easy. And we were able to reproduce without having
to use external framework or anything like that this
agentic workflow using plain Python code and the LLM API.
We're now using the OpenAI agents SDK. We're now using an agentic framework.
We're building everything ourselves to understand
under the hood what's going on with these agents or agentic workflows.
So now that we did that we can run this code.
And now we're going to make some tests. So the first one is going to be about
jokes. So pretty simple. Let's see if this works.
We're going to run it. So this is just tell me a joke about AI.
Perfect. It works perfectly. So as you can see
it created a joke. Now let's look at something that involves
writing the jokes but then also writing the file.
So that means that two actions have to be executed.
So let's see what happens here. All right, perfect. We can see that two iterations
were needed for this agent to finish and it seemed to have created the
the right file so we can take a look. Perfect. So it created five jokes, saved
them to file. Beautiful. Final test we're going to do
is the input for the web search agent. So we're going to research the latest
papers from 2025 about building agentic workflows.
And we're going to save that to a file called agentic workflows
25 summary. So now we're going to test this input
on our workflow and we're going to see if this works.
All right, so the router output is correct. Web search in the selected
agent was the web search agent so everything is working so far.
All right, perfect. We're done running. It took like a minute 13 seconds
but it seems like it searched the web and it saved to a file.
So we're going to look for that file. Beautiful. Look at that.
It looked, created a very nice report, has a bunch of papers.
I'm pretty certain that everything worked out and if I wasn't I could
inspect the intermediary outputs of this function.
But for now that's it. So today in this video you've learned
like eight levels of complexity to get to an
agentic workflow that uses an agent just as a step in a more complex
hybrid workflow. We've talked about LM calling, chaining,
routing, all the way up to agents and agentic workflows.
We've tried to do everything kind of from scratch
so that you understand the mechanics of function calling, structured outputs,
routing patterns, and things like that. I think those topics are really important
if you want to understand how to build off awesome agentic workflows.
And on an upcoming video I want to tackle from scratch as well.
Things like evaluation and making these systems work.
And I'll see you there. Thanks for watching. Don't forget to like and
subscribe and see you next time. Cheers.